Frances Perkins Lectures /3047 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frances Perkins Lectures
1957-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Perkins, Frances
/3047 AV
8 cubic feet
4.7 linear ft.
Transcripts, correspondence, audio cassette tapes.
7593130
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 12, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, May 22, 2014
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of lectures given by Miss Perkins at Cornell University in the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Subject areas covered are generally labor related with emphasis on the history of the labor movement during her appointment as Secretary of Labor. Discussed are the effect of the Roosevelt administration on labor; New York State labor; labor legislation; poverty; various labor leaders and labor organizations as well as significant labor incidents.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5017: Frances Perkins, Correspondence and Memorabilia 5065m: Frances Perkins Letter to Donald Stetson 5812: Interviews about Frances Perkins
7593130
- Lecture transcript no.1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on September 22, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on October 7, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on September 30, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on October 14, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on October 21, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on November 4, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on October 28, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on November 11, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on November 18, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on December 10, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on December 2, 1964.
- Lecture transcript no.12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture no date.
- Lecture transcript no.13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on January 6, 1965.
- Lecture transcript no.14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on January 13, 1965.
- Lecture transcript no.15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on January 20, 1965.
- Miss Perkins (Sept. 22) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Perkins Lecture (10/7/1964) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 9/30/1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Perkins (10/14/1964) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Cook-Perkins (10/21/1964) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Perkins Lecture Questions (11/4/1964) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Perkins Lectures (10/28/1964) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Perkins (11/11/1964) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cook-Perkins (11/18/1964) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Perkins (12/10/1964) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Cook-Perkins (12/2/1964) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Frances Perkins (no date) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Perkins (1/6/1965) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Perkins (1/13/1965) (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Perkins (1/20/1965) (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Frances Perkins - Triangle Shirtwaist Fire (Box 1, Folder 31)
  tape 3 --- pp28-36 [dup]
- Lecture transcript no.16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Hand edited typescript of "Al Smith As I Know Him" lecture, no date.
- Lecture transcript no.17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on November 7, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on February 6, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.19 a and b (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on February 13, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.20 a and b (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on February 27, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.21 a and b (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on March 13, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.22 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on April 3, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.23 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on April 17, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.24 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on May 1, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on December 16, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.26 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on April 24, 1957.
- Lecture transcript no.27 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Hand edited typescript of "One Sixth of the Nation" lecture, no date.
- Lecture transcript no.28 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Hand edited typescript of lecture given on March 17, 1965.
- Frances Perkins - The Al Smith I knew (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miss Frances Perkins -- Prof. Adams Class -- Nov. 7, 1957, Nov. 12, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miss F. Perkins - 2/6/1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Miss F. Perkins - 2/13/1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Miss F. Perkins -- 2/27/1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Recording Session -- March 13, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Recording session -- April 3, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Recording Session -- April 17, 1957, April 24, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Recording Session - May 1, 1957, May 8, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Lecture on New Deal to Miss Cook's class -- Dec. 16 ,1957 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Frances Perkins - address file (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 3)
  - tape #1 - 9/22/1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    2 cassettes
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 4)
  - tape #2 -- 10/7/1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 5)
  - tape #3 -- 9/30/1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 6)
  - tape #4 -- 10/14/1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 7)
  - tape #5 -- 10/21/1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 8)
  - tape #6 -- 11/4//1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 9)
  - tape #7 -- 10/28/1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 10)
  - tape #8 -- 11/11/1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 11)
  - tape #9 -- 11/18/1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 12)
  - tape #10 -- 11/18/1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 13)
  - tape #11 -- 12/21/1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 14)
  - tape #12 - no date (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 15)
  - tape #13 -- 1/6/1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 16)
  - tape #14 -- 1/13/1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 17)
  - tape #15 -- 1/20/1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 18)
  - tape #16 -- The Al Smith I knew (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 19)
  - tape #17 -- 11/12, 11/17 (no year) (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 20)
  - tape #18 -- 2/6/1957 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    3 cassettes
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 21)
  - tape #19 -- 2/13, 2/20/1957 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 22)
  - tape #20 -- 2/27, 3/6/1957 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 23)
  - tape #21 -- 3/13, 3/20/1957 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 24)
  - tape #22 -- 4/3, 4/10/1957 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 25)
  - tape #23 -- 4/17, 4/24/1957 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 26)
  - tape #24 -- 5/8, 12/16/1957 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Frances Perkins Lectures (Box 27)
  - tape #25 -- 12/16/1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)